MIKKEL CHAMBERS

Mikkel.P.Chambers@gmail.com • Mobile + 1 507 696 7190 • https://therealmpchambers.github.io/MPC Profile1/

Curiosity, Improvement, Strategy

Full stack web developer with a passion for creating user rich experiences through responsiveness and modern frontend code partnered with an analytical approach to designing beautiful architecture and maintaining back-end data and services. Previous work as an analyst and customer service guru has led towards an end user and designer mindset. This has led to an affirmed approach to provide innovative solutions to assist with usability, functionality, and elegance. Knowledgeable in front and back end web application design with a joy for designing responsive webpages, a curiosity for JavaScript, and enthusiasm for expanding expertise.

Experience with:

- CSS
- HTML

- BootstrapNode.JS
- MYSQL
- Express.JS
- Javascript
- GitHub
- Database
- JQuery
- Sequelize
- Restful API

CODING AND PROGRAMMING PROJECTS

CABINDAYS

A cabin scheduler app geared towards families that have cabins owned by two or more stakeholders. This app is designed to reduce stress, anxiety, and frustration when summer time and cabin scheduling come around. Responsible for front end design, implementing JQUERY frameworks, and JAVASCRIPT to smooth the UI. Acted as SME for GitHub interactions.

YOU'RE NIGHT OUT

Application focused on designing community-oriented events with minimal clicks and website visits. Acted as project manager managing schedules, deadlines, and component design. Responsible for HTML and CSS user design.

RETROPIE

Customized the operating system of a raspberry pi to allow for a virtual emulator focused on SEGA GENESIS and GameBoy Advanced games.

RPGs, GAMES, and TRIVIA

Designed several web applications with a focus on enjoyment. Responsible for front end and logic development. Utilized HTML, CSS, and JavaScript languages with implementation of several framework libraries.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

3WIRE – A MARMON/BERKSHIRE HATHAWAY COMPANY | Osseo, MN | 2015 – 2018

Sales and Operations Buyer

Supported the strategic direction outlined by Senior Leadership Team by establishing processes and procedures that reduced workload by 15%, improved delivery performance by an average of 4.7 days, and increased stock metrics by 23% while reducing total cost of inventory. Managed internal and external stakeholder relationships involving ontime delivery, tech services, and OEM/OCM manufacturing schedules. Designed and implemented excel macros and dashboards that automated redundant supply chain tasks.

MIKKEL CHAMBERS

TARGET CORPORATE | Minneapolis, MN | 2014-2015

Merchandise Specialist

Supported monthly vendor forecast cycle and ensured contract terms were met. Implemented agreements between Buyers and Vendors. Organized various marketing programs between miscellaneous business partners and ensured data accuracy for each program. Assisted and implemented inventory tactics to support assortment and merchandise plans while achieving service level and inventory turn targets which ensured that stores stayed in stock to support their ability to sell merchandise.

KLINE AUTO WORLD | Maplewood, MN | 2014-2014

Business Development Manager

Part of a new sales process focusing on a centralized sales call center. Developed processes involving outbound marketing campaigns, CRM data accuracy, and KPIs.

THREE DEEP MARKETING | Saint Paul, MN | 2013-2013

Contact Center Associate

Worked in a team environment-participated as a team leader and individual contributor depending on the project and client needs. Focused on growing market channels for customers through targeted programs. Assessed new and current clients advertising and marketing programs, making recommendations for improvement.

MYPILLOW INC | Chanhassen, MN | 2012 - 2013

Customer Service Supervisor

Managed 20-30 customer service direct reports, ensuring staff performed customer service principles and practices. Addressed customer service related issues with staff and customers. Supported continuous process improvement initiatives. Provided product manufacturing knowledge to staff and worked effectively with the supply chain.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF MINNESOTA - Saint Paul, MN

Certificate in Programming and Coding | September 2018 – March 2019

UNIVERSITY OF ST. THOMAS - Minneapolis, MN

Certified Professional Project Manager | Business Analytics 1 & 2 | Supply Chain | September 2015

BETHEL UNIVERSITY - Arden Hills, MN

Master of Arts | Communication Studies | September 2012 – Present

NORTHWESTERN UNIVERSITY - St. Paul, MN

Bachelor of Arts | Communication Studies | September 2009 – May 2012

MEMBERSHIP & VOLUNTEER ACTIVITIES

UNITED STATES TENNIS ASSOCIATION | 2017 – Present

MEN'S RECREATIONAL SOCCER LEAGUE | 2017 - Present

LAMBDA PI ETA-XI XI HONOR SOCIETY | 2010 - 2012

UNIVERSITY OF NORTHWESTERN | Journalist for Student Newspaper "The Column": 2010-2012